relationshipscience.com 2018-08-12

# Privacy Notice for relationshipscience.com 22.05.18

** Relationship Science  **

** PRIVACY POLICY  **

Last Updated: May 24, 2018 

This privacy policy explains how Relationship Science (" **RelSci** ," " **we** ", “ **our** ” and " **us** "), collects, uses, shares and protects information obtained from visitors to this [www.relationshipscience.com](http://www.relationshipscience.com/) website (the " **Site** ") and RelSci Pro and RelSci Lite subscribers. 

This Privacy Policy, together with the Terms of Use constitute a single agreement between you and us (the “ **Agreement** ”).  Please read this Privacy Policy carefully.  **By visiting the Site and providing information to us you consent to our collection, processing, storage, sharing and use of your information consistent with the terms of this Privacy Policy and to all terms and conditions contained in the** Terms of Use ** . If you do not agree to be bound by these terms, your only choice is not to use our Site  **. 

** NOTICE TO EU DATA SUBJECTS (INCLUDING VISITORS TO THE SITE FROM THE EU AND INDIVIDUALS FROM THE EU WHOSE DATA WE USE TO PROVIDE THE SERVICES)  **

** Please read this Privacy Policy and accompanying Terms of Use carefully and click  ****here** ** for further information about your privacy rights.  **

** Personal Information and Other Data We Collect  **

We consider all information that can be used to identify a specific individual, such as name, mailing address, email address and telephone number, to be personally identifiable information (“ **PII** ” or “ **personal information** ”).  

RelSci collects several types of information about or relating to you, including: 

  * Information that you voluntarily provide to us, including personal information, such as when you create an account on the Site, including your name and contact details, email address, and phone number 

  * Information about your social and business connections (collectively, “ **Contacts** ”) that you choose affirmatively, or enable us to, upload to the Site, including the Client Data (as such term is defined in the  Terms of Use ). We collect information about your Contacts when you directly input it to the Site, and also when you synchronize non-Site content, such as your electronic address book (e.g., your contact information stored on an email server, on your computer or mobile phone) with your account on the Site 

  * Information about you and your Contacts that we obtain from third parties, such as data aggregators, public sources, and advertising networks, which we may combine with the information received about you and your Contacts through our Site 

  * Information about you and your visits to our Site, but which does not specifically identify you, such as the pages you view, search terms you enter, and other actions you take in connection with the Site. We may also collect certain information from the browser, server, computer or other device you used to come to our Site, such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type and language, the operating system on your computer or device, the device identifier for your mobile device, the time you accessed our Site, what country or general geographic area you are located in, the Uniform Resource Locator (URL) of the website that referred you to our Site and to which URL you browse away from our Site if you click on a link on our Site.  We will collect this information regardless of whether you subscribe to any of our Services (as defined in the  Terms of Use ) or only visit the Site for informational purposes.  This information may be collected automatically when you navigate our Site.  While this information does not in and of itself identify you, we may maintain it or associate it with personal information that we collect in other ways or receive from third parties.  Doing this helps us improve our Site and to deliver a better and more personalized service to you, including enabling us to store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Site according to your individual interests, speed up your searches, and recognize you when you return to our Site. Additionally, persons to whom we make such non-identifying information available as described in this Privacy Policy may be able to aggregate such data with other data available to them and thus be able to identify you. 

You may provide us your information when you register to use our Site, when you subscribe to receive our Services, when you create a user account, when you use one of our online tools, when you carry out a transaction on our Site (such as making a payment), or when you report a problem with our Site.  You understand that by creating an account, uploading information to our Site, or interacting with us in any of these ways, we and other users of the Site or our Services will be able to identify you. 

**Cookies**

When you visit the Site, whether or not you are a subscriber, we may send one or more "cookies" (small data files) to your browser to uniquely identify you, let us help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the Site. A cookie may convey anonymous information about how you browse the Site to us, but does not collect personal information about you unless you are a subscriber to one of our Services, in which case your name may be included in the cookie to facilitate faster access to the Site. 

We may use both persistent and session cookies.  A persistent cookie remains on your computer after you close your browser so that it can be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Site. Most persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser's directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears or becomes inactive after you close your browser. 

You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent.  However, keep in mind that some features of the Site may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled. 

**Do Not Track**

We will attempt to respect your wishes when you set your browser to “do not track” (a setting that your Internet browser may make available to you, which allows you to choose not to have your online behavior tracked).  However, we cannot guarantee that in all instances your information will not be tracked by our Site or by a third party performing services for us (such as Google Analytics). 

**Log Files**

Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access a web page. When you use the Site, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, IP address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information. 

**Children**

Minors (those under the age of 18) may not use the Site. We do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 18, and no part of the Site is designed to attract anyone under the age of 18. Because we do not intentionally collect any information from children under the age of 18, we also do not knowingly share or disclose such information to third parties. If you have reason to believe that a child under 18 years of age has provided us with personal information, please contact us at Privacy@RelSci.com and we will take appropriate action under applicable law. 

** How We Use Your Information  **

We may use your personal and non-personal information, information about your Contacts (whether PII or not), and other content and information you provide to us or that we acquire from data aggregators, ad networks, public sources and other third parties (collectively, your “ **information** ” as used in this Privacy Policy) in the following ways: 

  * to present our Site and its contents to you
  * to provide you with information, products or services that you request from us 
  * to notify you of opportunities, developments or offers available through RelSci, its affiliates, or business partners 
  * to provide personalized content and services on the Site and on other RelSci websites 
  * to aggregate your information with information provided by others 
  * to offer combined data sets, including your personal information and that of your Contacts, to third parties as part of our Services 
  * to understand what our target market is and determine where and how to advertise our services to others 
  * to customize, analyze, and improve our products, services (including the content on the Site), technologies, communications and relationship with you 
  * to customize your experience on our Site
  * to notify you about new tools and features on the Site 
  * to notify you about changes to our Site, to the Terms of Use , or this Privacy Policy
  * to respond to your inquiries and requests for Services or assistance 
  * to allow you to participate in interactive features available on our Site 
  * to track content and users as necessary to comply with applicable law 
  * for our own research and development purposes and for the improvement of our Services 
  * to provide you a better, more intuitive experience on our Site, or 
  * otherwise, as you may consent or we may notify you at the time of collection 

You agree that information you provide to us and that you upload to our Site may be visible to third parties and may be used by us to provide our Services, including to other visitors and subscribers to our Site.  The personal information that you provide to us may reveal or allow others to identify aspects of your life and that of your Contacts that are not expressly shared by you (for example, you may not provide on the Site your year of birth, but you may post or provide us with the date upon which you graduated from high school, allowing us and other users or our business partners to discern your approximate age). 

By providing your personal information on the Site you are expressly and voluntarily accepting our terms of use and this Privacy Policy, consenting to our use of such information in our business, and to our storing, using, processing and transmitting of your personal information in the ways set out in this Privacy Policy.   

** Use of your Information by Third Parties  **

We share your information, as you provided it to us, or aggregated with data we collect from others or with third party data, across our different services among all of our affiliated companies (meaning entities controlled by us, controlling us, or under common control with us).   Any information you post or upload to our Site, and any content you provide to us, may be seen by others.  We may also share this information with third parties, whether as part of our Services or in connection with other transactions in which we may engage.  You specifically consent to this sharing. 

We make certain third party tools and services available, such as software widgets, tools or applications, which allow you to synchronize your desktop and/or mobile device’s calendar, email or contacts residing on third party applications with our Services.  Your use of these tools means that you have granted permission to us and to the applicable third parties to access your information and information about your Contacts.  We and these third parties may also be able to access your email, calendar and other accounts, and we and they may collect and store some or all of this information for our/their own purposes. 

We may use Google Analytics, a service offered by Google, Inc., and other analytical tools to track your activities on our Site, including your browsing history.  We use this information to improve the quality of our Services.  Google Analytics also may collect non-personal information about you, your computer and the network you use to connect to our Site. 

We do not, at present, use any of your or your Contacts’ personal information for purposes of behavioral or targeted advertising, but we may in the future begin to do so.  If we do, we will notify you prior to beginning such activities.  If we do add such activities, you understand that after notification to you, some content or applications, including advertisements, on the Site may be served by third-parties, including advertisers, ad networks and servers, content providers, and application providers. These third parties may use cookies alone or in conjunction with web beacons or other tracking technologies to collect information about you when you use our Website.  The information they collect may be associated with your personal information or they may collect information, including personal information, about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services. They may use this information to provide you with interest-based (behavioral) advertising or other targeted content. We do not control these third parties' tracking technologies or how they may be used. If you have any questions about an advertisement or other targeted content, you should contact the responsible provider directly. 

** How We Communicate with You  **

We may communicate with you through e-mail, notices posted on the Site, and messages sent to you through the Services.  Examples of these communications include: (1) welcome and engagement communications informing you about how to best use our Services, new features, etc.; (2) service communications, such as messages to inform you of service unavailability, security, and other issues about our Services; and (3) promotional communications, which may contain promotional information about our Services, or those coming directly or on behalf of our partners. 

We may also send you surveys or polls, requesting your feedback regarding our Services.  Your responses are appreciated, and help us improve the quality of our Services. 

** Disclosure of Your Information  **

We may disclose and share with third parties and our affiliates aggregated information about our users, and other non-personal information, without restriction. 

We may share any personal information obtained from you or as a result of your activities on our Site, and information about you and your Contacts which we collected through third party sources: 

  * with third parties, including our affiliates, and with our contractors, service providers and other parties we use to support our business (e.g., website hosting providers, credit card processors and processing banks, server hosting providers, etc.). These third party service providers (“ **Providers** ”) perform functions on our behalf, like sending out and distributing our administrative and promotional emails. We may share your information with such Providers to remove repetitive information on customer lists, analyze data, provide marketing assistance, provide search results and links, process credit card payments, operate the website, troubleshoot, and provide customer service 

  * with a buyer or successor to our business in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, or other sale or transfer of some or all of our assets or voting securities, whether as a going concern, or in bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which information held by us is among the assets to be transferred 

  * With third parties for the purpose of offering our products and services 

  * With third parties who wish to acquire your information to use in their business 

  * If required to do so by law or by court order

  * If we believe that it is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request 

  * To protect the safety of any person

  * To address fraud, security or technical issues

  * To protect our rights or property 

We may also share or disclose your information with your consent, such as if you choose to sign on to the Site through a third-party service, or using credentials from a third party website, such as Facebook.  Please note however, that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of third party websites (even if we offered links to third party websites on the Site) and those third parties are under no obligation to comply with this Privacy Policy.  Before visiting another website and before providing any information to the party that operates or advertises on that third party website, users should review the privacy policy and practices of that website to determine how information that they collect from users will be handled. 

**Where Your Information Will be Stored**

Your information will be held, by us or our service providers, in the United States. If your information is gathered outside the United States, it may be transferred to RelSci's United States offices to be used consistent with the terms of this Privacy Policy, and it may be transferred to and shared with any of RelSci's worldwide locations. You may request a full list of all subsidiaries and affiliates of RelSci by contacting us at Privacy@RelSci.com. 

** Your use of the Site from outside the United States of America is at your own risk.  We cannot and do not guarantee that our business operations, infrastructure or security measures comply with any laws in your country of origin or residence  ** .  **You specifically consent to the application of United States law in all matters concerning the Site, your use of it, and our collection, use, sharing and processing of your personal information and all Client Data**. 

IN USING OUR SERVICES, YOU REPRESENT, WARRANT AND AGREE THAT YOU HAVE THE RIGHT TO, AND THE CONSENT OF ALL APPLICABLE THIRD PARTIES, TO PROVIDE ALL CLIENT DATA, INCLUDING THE PERSONAL INFORMATION OF YOUR CONTACTS (INCLUDING THOSE LOCATED OUTSIDE THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA) TO RELATIONSHIP SCIENCE.  YOU AGREE TO DEFEND AND INDEMNIFY RELATIONSHIP SCIENCE AND ITS AFFILIATES AND THEIR RESPECTIVE DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES, SHAREHOLDERS, MEMBERS, MANAGERS, AGENTS AND REPRESETNATIVES FORM AND AGAINST ALL CLAIMS, LOSSES, DAMAGES, SUITS OR PROCEEDINGS THAT MAY ARISE AS A RESULT OF YOUR BREACH OF THE FOREGOING WARRANTY. 

** How We Protect Your Information  **

RelSci uses commercially reasonable physical, administrative, and technical safeguards in an attempt to preserve the integrity and security of your information. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure, and we can therefore not guarantee the security of your information transmitted to or through our Site.  Any transmission of information is at your own risk. 

In the event that PII is compromised as a result of a breach of security, we will promptly notify those persons located in the United States of America whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law. 

We will make reasonable efforts to notify subscribers in other countries if there has been a breach of security involving their personal information, but cannot guarantee that such notifications will be made in compliance with applicable local foreign laws or that they will be timely. 

** Your Choices About Your Information  **

You may, of course, decline to submit your personal information or that of your Contacts through the Site, in which case RelSci may not be able to provide certain Services to you. 

You may update or correct your account information and email preferences at any time by logging in to your account on the Site. 

You may cancel your account at any time, consistent with the Terms of Use .  Note, however, that if you cancel your account on the Site, we will retain all information you have already provided, and may continue to use such information consistent with the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

**Links**

The Site may contain links to websites that Relationship Science does not operate. Please make sure when you leave the Site that you have read all privacy policies, Terms of Use and other governing documents applicable to such third party websites that you visit, as this Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by our Site to any other website to which it is posted. 

Relationship Science is not responsible for and does not monitor the content of third party websites, and you should direct any concerns regarding those websites to their respective site administrators or webmasters. 

** Your California Privacy Rights  **

California Civil Code Section § 1798.83, known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits users of our Site who are California residents to request and obtain from us a list of what personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding year, and the names and addresses of those third parties.  You may request this information from us no more than once a year, but such request will be handled by us free of charge to you.  To make such a request, please send an email to Privacy@RelSci.com. 

** Changes to This Policy  **

We may make changes to our Services over time, and in the future may make new or different tools available to synchronize information with our Services that are not available today.  Such improvements in our service may involve collection of new data about you or your Contacts.  Furthermore, we may enter into partnerships with new third parties, and in doing so, such additional third parties may be allowed access to your information.  If we start collecting substantially new types of information or using or sharing it in materially different ways, we will update this Privacy Policy.  Please be sure to review this Privacy Policy often, as we may amend this policy as such service offerings expand. 

RelSci may update this policy in its discretion from time to time. Any changes to this Privacy Policy in the future will be posted to the Site.  Your continued use of our Site after the revised terms are posted will indicate your consent to the amended terms of this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use .  If you do not agree with any amendments to the Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy, please stop using the Site and notify us immediately at privacy@relsci.com. 

**Contact**

All comments, queries and requests relating to our use of your information are welcomed and should be addressed to the following e-mail address: _privacy@relsci.com_  or to Legal Department, 5 Pennsylvania Plaza, 15th Floor, New York, NY 10001. 

** In addition to reading the Privacy Policy and accompanying Terms of Use carefully, please note the further information below about your privacy rights.  **

**_ Who we are  _ **

The Site and our Services are operated by Relationship Science LLC of 5 Pennsylvania Plaza, 15th Floor, New York, NY 10001. 

The data controller responsible for your personal information processed via the Site or in relation to the Services is Relationship Science LLC. 

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or want to exercise any data subject rights you may have in relation to the Site and/or the Services (as explained below), please contact us by sending an email to [privacy@relsci.com](mailto:privacy@relsci.com) or contacting us at the Legal Department, 5 Pennsylvania Plaza, 15th Floor, New York, NY 10001, USA. 

**_ Location of data and processing  _ **

_ Your personal information will be held, by us or our service providers, in the United States. We provide the Services to you from the United States and use our subsidiary in India to process personal information as part of the provision of the Services.  _ You may request a full list of all subsidiaries and affiliates of ours by contacting us at [ privacy@relsci.com ](mailto:privacy@relsci.com).

**_ Legal basis of processing  _ **

Our processing of your personal information may be necessary for the performance of a contract with you or to take steps at your request to enter into a contract. 

Our processing of your personal information may be necessary for complying with our legal obligations. 

Our processing of your personal information may be necessary for our legitimate interests or those of a third party.  This includes the purposes set out in the bullet points in this Privacy Policy under the heading “How We Use Your Information” except where, for example, we do so pursuant to a legal obligation or the performance of a contract with you.   

Our processing of your personal information might take place on the basis of your consent, given at the time and point of collection on the Site, for one or more specific purposes. 

**_ How long do we keep your personal information  _ **

We will keep your personal information in accordance with our retention policies and applicable law but we will not keep it for longer than is necessary. Where we have a business relationship with you and unless otherwise agreed we will keep your personal information for the duration of that business relationship with you and for a certain period afterwards. Where we do not have a business relationship with you, for example, where you are a visitor to the Site or use our consumer website at [ www.relationshipscience.com ](http://www.relationshipscience.com/) , we will retain your personal information for our legitimate business interests for at least 38 months subject to you exercising any data subject rights as described below. In considering how long to keep your personal information, we take into account the nature of the information, the nature of the relationship with you, the relevance to our business of the information, and our obligations to comply with applicable laws and regulations. 

**_ Confidentiality and security  _ **

We are committed to keeping the personal information provided to us secure and we will take reasonable precautions to protect personal information from loss, misuse or alteration. We have implemented information security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal information that we have under our control from: unauthorized access; improper use or disclosure; unauthorized modification; and unlawful destruction or accidental loss. 

All of our employees, workers and data processors (i.e. those who process your personal data on our behalf), who have access to, and are associated with, the processing of personal information, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of the personal information of all visitors to the Site and all users of our Services. 

**_ Data subject rights  _ **

You have the following rights in relation to the personal information we hold about you. Please note that these rights are subject to certain exemptions which may be applicable to any request you make. 

_ Your right of access  _

If you ask us, we will confirm whether we are processing your personal information and, subject to any applicable exemptions, provide you with a copy of that personal information (along with certain other details) within the timescales or extended timescales provided for by the EU General Data Protection Regulation for complex requests, or where applicable, provide you with an explanation as to why we will not be complying with your request. If you require additional copies, we may need to charge a reasonable fee. 

_ Your right to rectification  _

If the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete, you are entitled to have it rectified. If you are entitled to rectification and if we have shared your personal information with others, we will let them know about the rectification where possible and where this would not involve disproportionate effort. If you ask us, where possible and lawful to do so, we will also tell you who we have shared your personal information with so that you can contact them directly. 

_ Your right to erasure  _

You can ask us to delete or remove your personal information in some circumstances such as where we no longer need it or if you withdraw your consent (where applicable because that was the legal basis on which we were processing your personal information). If you are entitled to erasure and if we have shared your personal information with others, we will take reasonable steps to inform those others where possible and where this would not involve disproportionate effort. If you ask us, where it is possible and lawful for us to do so, we will also tell you who we have shared your personal information with so that you can contact them directly. 

_ Your right to restrict processing  _

You can ask us to ‘block’ or suppress the processing of your personal information in certain circumstances such as where you contest the accuracy of that personal information or you object to us. If you are entitled to restriction and if we have shared your personal information with others, we will let them know about the restriction where it is possible for us to do so. If you ask us, where it is possible and lawful for us to do so, we will also tell you who we have shared your personal information with so that you can contact them directly. 

_ Your right to data portability  _

With effect from 25 May 2018, you have the right, in certain circumstances, to obtain personal information you have provided us with (in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format) and to reuse it elsewhere or to ask us to transfer this to a third party of your choice. 

_ Your right to object  _

You can ask us to stop processing your personal information, and we will do so, if we are relying on our own or someone else’s legitimate interests to process your personal information, except if we can demonstrate compelling legal grounds for the processing; or processing your personal information for direct marketing. 

_ Your rights in relation to automated decision-making and profiling  _

You have the right not to be subject to a decision when it is based on automatic processing, including profiling, if it produces a legal effect or similarly significantly affects you, unless such profiling is necessary for entering into, or the performance of, a contract between you and us. 

_ Your right to withdraw consent  _

If we rely on your consent (or explicit consent) as our legal basis for processing your personal information, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. 

_ Your right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority  _

If you have a concern about any aspect of our privacy practices, including the way we have handled your personal information, you can report it to your local supervisory authority (data regulator). 

A list of contact details for all EU supervisory authorities can be found at: [ http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm ](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm)
